var chapters = [
//   { chapter: 1, title: "Retail Banking" },
//   { chapter: 2, title: "Deposit Accounts" },
//   { chapter: 3, title: "Opening of Deposit Accounts" },
//   { chapter: 4, title: "Current Account" },
//   { chapter: 5, title: "Savings Account" },
//   { chapter: 6, title: "Fixed Deposit Account" },
//   { chapter: 7, title: "Certificate of Deposit" },
//   { chapter: 8, title: "Nomination" },
//   { chapter: 9, title: "Unclaimed Deposits" },
//   { chapter: 10, title: "Deceased Depositors" },
//   { chapter: 11, title: "Settlement of Claims in Respect of Missing Person" },
//   { chapter: 12, title: "General Account Monitoring And Operations" },
//   { chapter: 13, title: "Prohibitions" },
//   { chapter: 14, title: "Deposit Insurance" },
//   { chapter: 15, title: "Retail Loans" },
//   { chapter: 16, title: "Personal Loans" },
//   { chapter: 17, title: "Consumer Durable Loans" },
//   { chapter: 18, title: "Loans to Professionals and Self Employed" },
//   { chapter: 19, title: "Education Loan" },
//   { chapter: 20, title: "Loan For Vocational Education And Training" },
  { chapter: 21, title: "Vehicle Loan" },
  { chapter: 22, title: "Loan Against Shares And Debentures" },
  { chapter: 23, title: "Housing Finance" },
  { chapter: 24, title: "Reverse Mortgage Loan" },
  { chapter: 25, title: "Retail Credit Analysis" },
  { chapter: 26, title: "Fair Practice Code For Lenders" },
  { chapter: 27, title: "Recovery Agents" },
  { chapter: 28, title: "Mutual Funds" },
  { chapter: 29, title: "Dematerialization of Shares" },
  { chapter: 30, title: "Bancassurance" },
  { chapter: 31, title: "Bank Drafts" },
  { chapter: 32, title: "Pay Orders" },
  { chapter: 33, title: "Travellers Cheques" },
  { chapter: 34, title: "Clearing" },
  { chapter: 35, title: "Truncated cheque clearance" },
  { chapter: 36, title: "Electronic Clearing Service" },
  { chapter: 37, title: "National Electronic Clearing service" },
  { chapter: 38, title: "Speed Clearing" },
  { chapter: 39, title: "Asian Clearing Union" },
  { chapter: 40, title: "Standing Instructions" },
  { chapter: 41, title: "Mail and Wire  Telegraphic Transfers" },
  { chapter: 42, title: "Money Transfer Services Scheme" },
  { chapter: 43, title: "Real Time Gross Settlement" },
  { chapter: 44, title: "Electronic Funds Transfer" },
  { chapter: 45, title: "National Electronic Funds Transfer" },
  { chapter: 46, title: "Swift" },
  { chapter: 47, title: "Indo-Nepal Remittance Facility Scheme" },
  { chapter: 48, title: "Cash" },
  { chapter: 49, title: "Electronic Banking" },
  { chapter: 50, title: "Telephone Banking" },
  { chapter: 51, title: "Mobile Banking" },
  { chapter: 52, title: "Cards" },
  { chapter: 53, title: "Telemarketing" },
  { chapter: 54, title: "Doorstep Banking" },
  { chapter: 55, title: "Safe Deposit Lockers" },
  { chapter: 56, title: "Safe Custody" },
];

var allQuestionAnswers = [
  {"question":"Retail Banking is ………………… to individuals.","options":["Facility","Services","Both above","None"],"answer":"Both above","chapter":1,"marks":1},{"question":"New Generation banks are……………………","options":["Customer Centric","Focused","Driven","All above"],"answer":"All above","chapter":1,"marks":1},{"question":"Banking has become functionally segmented in to……………..","options":["Retail Banking and corporate Banking","Trade Finance","Merchant Banking and Private Banking","All above"],"answer":"All above","chapter":1,"marks":1},{"question":"Because of enormous demand Banks have not had the time to …………most of their new inductees","options":["Train","Absorb","Reject","Coordinate with"],"answer":"Train","chapter":1,"marks":1},{"question":"To develop the retail banking in underdeveloped areas what recent action government has taken?","options":["Open branches","Provide Mobile banking","Financial inclusion","Publicity"],"answer":"Financial inclusion","chapter":1,"marks":1},
  {"question":"The relationship between a banker and customers begins when the customer …………","options":["Opens an account","Deposit an amount in account","Any one above","Both above"],"answer":"Both above","chapter":2,"marks":1},{"question":"What are the different types of deposit accounts?","options":["Demand deposits","Time deposits","Term Deposits","Both a & b"],"answer":"Both a & b","chapter":2,"marks":1},{"question":"Following types of deposit are called Demand Deposit/ s…………………….","options":["Current account","Savings account","Call Deposit","All above"],"answer":"All above","chapter":2,"marks":1},{"question":"A deposit received by the bank for a fixed period and which is withdrawable only after expiry of the said fixed period is called as ………………….","options":["Fixed deposit","Demand deposit","Current deposit","Any one above"],"answer":"Fixed deposit","chapter":2,"marks":1},{"question":"Under what circumstances banks are not required to obtain prior concurrence of RBI to launch new Deposit mobilisation schemes?","options":["Scheme is approved by Board of Directors","Banks ensuring RBI guidelines are being followed","Any one above","Both above"],"answer":"Both above","chapter":2,"marks":1},
  {"question":"Large number of frauds are perpetrated in banks due to………………..","options":["Fictitious names","Irregular payment of cheques , manipulation of accounts","Unauthorised operations in accounts","All above"],"answer":"All above","chapter":3,"marks":1},{"question":"An account can be opened by anyone who………………..","options":["Wish to open account","Is forced to open","Enter in to valid contract","All above"],"answer":"Enter in to valid contract","chapter":3,"marks":1},{"question":"From whom bank considers that introduction is necessary for opening account?","options":["From any one","Known person in the society","Existing customers","All above"],"answer":"Existing customers","chapter":3,"marks":1},{"question":"Introduction should be by……………………..","options":["Introduction should be by……………………..","Respectable person of the local community","Another banker","Any one above"],"answer":"Any one above","chapter":3,"marks":1},{"question":"RBI has advised banks to incorporate a certificate in account opening form confirming …………….of the prospective customers signed by the introducer.","options":["Identity","Occupation","Address","All above"],"answer":"All above","chapter":3,"marks":1},{"question":"In case of minor, whose photograph is required?","options":["Mother","Father","Guardian","Relative"],"answer":"Guardian","chapter":3,"marks":1},{"question":"Can photograph be substituted for the specimen signature? …………Yes or No","options":["Yes","No"],"answer":"No","chapter":3,"marks":1},{"question":"Why bank should obtain the full and complete address of the depositor?","options":["To send the cheque book","To send the birthday and other greetings","To trace him when required","as per RBI regulation"],"answer":"To trace him when required","chapter":3,"marks":1},{"question":"PAN / GIR of account openers with initial deposit of Rs…………….and above must be obtained.","options":["20,000","50,000","100,000","500,000"],"answer":"50,000","chapter":3,"marks":1},{"question":"What is the provision in lieu of PAN?","options":["Obtain declaration","Obtain letter from neighbour","Obtain form 60","Seek exemption from income tax department"],"answer":"Obtain form 60","chapter":3,"marks":1},
  {"question":"A form of deposit wherefrom withdrawals are allowed any number of times depending up on the balance in the account is called as ………………..","options":["Savings account","Terms deposit account","Current account","Recurring deposit account"],"answer":"Current account","chapter":4,"marks":1},{"question":"Why current account is opened?","options":["For savings purpose","To pay the amount to relatives","Commercial and business","To take a loan from financial institutions"],"answer":"Commercial and business","chapter":4,"marks":1},{"question":"Who opens current account?","options":["Person who wants to save money","Entity or person having commercial interest","Person who has taken loan","Person having social interest"],"answer":"Entity or person having commercial interest","chapter":4,"marks":1},{"question":"What is important for bank to open a current account?","options":["Identity","Occupation","Address","All above"],"answer":"All above","chapter":4,"marks":1},{"question":"Current account can be opened with operation instructions as ………………","options":["Singly","Joint","Either or survivor","Any one of the above"],"answer":"Any one of the above","chapter":4,"marks":1},{"question":"If current account customer demand for large number of cheque books will it be obligatory on the part of bank to provide?....................Yes or No","options":["Yes","No"],"answer":"Yes","chapter":4,"marks":1},{"question":"On receipt of notice of assignment of the credit balance in the account of customer  to third party whether account will be allowed operate or bank will stop operations in account?","options":["Allow operations on request","Stop operation in account","all above"],"answer":"Stop operation in account","chapter":4,"marks":1},{"question":"Whether interest can be paid on the balances in the current account? …Yes or No","options":["Yes","No"],"answer":"No","chapter":4,"marks":1},{"question":"Whether in banks are permitted to pay the interest on the balances maintained with them in the account of Regional rural banks (RRB) sponsored by them?","options":["Permitted","Not permitted","none of the above"],"answer":"Permitted","chapter":4,"marks":1},{"question":"What is dormant account?","options":["No customer initiation transaction for 6 months","No customer initiation transaction for 1 year","No customer initiation transaction for 2 year","No customer initiation transaction for 3 year"],"answer":"No customer initiation transaction for 2 year","chapter":4,"marks":1},
  {"question":"“At the time of opening the account, bank must advise customers of requirement of maintaining minimum balance and levying of charges if minimum  balance is not maintained”……True or false","options":["True","False"],"answer":"True","chapter":5,"marks":1},{"question":"“Operations in the account should not be stopped even though bank receives the notice of death of customer, insanity, insolvency, receipt of garnishee order from the court”…………….True or false","options":["True","False"],"answer":"False","chapter":5,"marks":1},{"question":"Companies governed by companies act 1956 which have been licensed by central government under section 25 of the act are permitted not to add to their names the word “……………”","options":["Limited","Private Limited","Public limited","Any one above"],"answer":"Any one above","chapter":5,"marks":1},{"question":"Whether facilities provided under financial inclusion are chargeable by bank?....Yes or No","options":["Yes","No"],"answer":"No","chapter":5,"marks":1},{"question":"Holders of “Basic Savings Bank Deposit account” will be ………….for opening any other savings bank deposit account in that bank.","options":["Eligible","Not eligible","all the above"],"answer":"Not eligible","chapter":5,"marks":1},{"question":"A deposit account which is subject to restrictions as to the number of withdrawals as also the amount of withdrawals permitted by the bank during any specified period  is called as …………","options":["Savings account","Current account","Recurring deposit account","Fixed deposit account"],"answer":"Savings account","chapter":5,"marks":1},{"question":"With regards to those who intend to keep balances not exceeding Rs……in all their accounts taken together and the total credit in all advances taken is not expected to exceed Rs.100, 000 can open the Savings account.","options":["10,000","25,000","50,000","100,000"],"answer":"50,000","chapter":5,"marks":1},{"question":"The RBI has also asked banks to make available a ………………..either with nil or very low minimum balances that would make such accounts accessible to vast section of population.","options":["Ordinary savings bank account","Basic no frill account","Special savings bank account","No balance account"],"answer":"Basic no frill account","chapter":5,"marks":1},{"question":"The ……………………states that no overdraft on regular basis should be permitted in a savings bank account.","options":["Reserve Bank of India","Indian Banks association","Government of India","Bank policy"],"answer":"Indian Banks association","chapter":5,"marks":1},{"question":"Additional interest of ………percent per annum is payable to Staff of the bank maintaining saving account","options":["½","1","2","3"],"answer":"1","chapter":5,"marks":1},
  {"question":"Minimum period of fixed deposit is ……………….","options":["7days","30 days","365 days","120 months"],"answer":"7days","chapter":6,"marks":1},{"question":"Maximum period of the fixed deposit is …………","options":["7days","30 days","365 days","120 months"],"answer":"120 months","chapter":6,"marks":1},{"question":"On deposit less that ………..months or where the quarter is incomplete, interest should be paid on the actual number of days reckoning the year at 365 days.","options":["1","3","5","6"],"answer":"3","chapter":6,"marks":1},{"question":"What is the minimum amount of interest payable on fixed deposit account?","options":["Rs.1","Rs.10","Rs.25","Rs.50"],"answer":"Rs.1","chapter":6,"marks":1},{"question":"What is the amount less than which Scheduled banks are permitted to give, at their discretion an additional interest ½ %?","options":["Rs. 15 Crs","Rs. 20 Crs","Rs. 25 Crs","Rs.30 Crs"],"answer":"Rs. 25 Crs","chapter":6,"marks":1},{"question":"Tax need not be collected if depositor files form …………….or certificate under section 197 (1) of the income tax act. 1961","options":["15 H","15 G","Any one above","Both above"],"answer":"Any one above","chapter":6,"marks":1},{"question":"Under what circumstances interest is not paid on pre mature closure of fixed deposit?","options":["If requested by depositor","As per banks policy","Provided minimum period prescribed is not completed","Any one above"],"answer":"Provided minimum period prescribed is not completed","chapter":6,"marks":1},{"question":"Deposit may be renewed before maturity provided……………","options":["It is renewed before the date of maturity","The period of renewal is longer than remaining period of the original deposit","Any one above","Both above"],"answer":"Both above","chapter":6,"marks":1},{"question":"If the deposit matures on Sunday/ Holiday / Non working day the bank should interest at the originally contracted rate on the deposit amount for these days also and paid on …………","options":["Day of maturity","Preceding day","Succeeding day","Any day"],"answer":"Succeeding day","chapter":6,"marks":1},{"question":"Deposit can be renewed, provided the depositor approaches the bank ………..from the date of maturity of deposit.","options":["Within 14 days","After 14 days","Between 14 days"],"answer":"Within 14 days","chapter":6,"marks":1},
  {"question":"Certificates can be issued by scheduled commercial bank and select all India Financial institutions that have been permitted by RBI to ………………..","options":["Raise short term resources","Raise long term resources","Any one above","Both above"],"answer":"Raise short term resources","chapter":7,"marks":1},{"question":"Is there any for issuance of CD by banks? ……………Yes or No","options":["Yes","No"],"answer":"No","chapter":7,"marks":1},{"question":"What is the minimum amount for issuance of Certificate of Deposit?","options":["1 lack","3 lacs","5 lacs","10 lacs"],"answer":"1 lack","chapter":7,"marks":1},{"question":"Whether NRI can subscribe for Certificate of Deposit? ……Yes or No","options":["Yes","No","Yes , On reptriable basis","Yes,  only on non reptriable basis"],"answer":"Yes,  only on non reptriable basis","chapter":7,"marks":1},{"question":"“Certificate of deposit in physical form are freely transferable  by endorsement and delivery” ………………..True or False","options":["True","False"],"answer":"True","chapter":7,"marks":1},{"question":"If the maturity date of certificate of deposit happens to be holiday, the issuing bank / FI should make the payment on…………….","options":["Date of maturity only","Immediate preceding working day","Immediate succeeding working day"],"answer":"Immediate preceding working day","chapter":7,"marks":1},{"question":"In case of loss of physical certificate of deposit, duplicate certificates can be issued after compliance of ………………………","options":["Giving notice in local news paper","15 days after notice issued in local news paper","Execution of indemnity bond by investor","All above"],"answer":"All above","chapter":7,"marks":1},
  {"question":"Whether association, trust, societies can be nominated by individuals? …Yes or No","options":["Yes","No"],"answer":"No","chapter":8,"marks":1},{"question":"How many nominees can be appointed in case of joint accounts?","options":["1","2","As per wish of depositors","As advised by bank"],"answer":"1","chapter":8,"marks":1},{"question":"In case of joint account at what point of time nominees right arises?","options":["When deposit matures","After the death of one depositor","After death of all depositors","In case of dispute"],"answer":"After death of all depositors","chapter":8,"marks":1},{"question":"A……………must register in its books nomination, cancellation and variation.","options":["Depositor","Account holder","Bank","Any one above"],"answer":"Bank","chapter":8,"marks":1},{"question":"If customer refuses to nominate what Bank should do?","options":["Obtain letter","Bank should explain the advantages of nomination","If declines, noting on the account opening form","All above"],"answer":"All above","chapter":8,"marks":1},{"question":"Is the nomination facility available for savings account opened for credit of pension? –Yes or No","options":["Yes","No"],"answer":"Yes","chapter":8,"marks":1},
  // {"question":"What is unclaimed deposit?","options":["7 days","15 days","30 days","45 days"],"answer":"30 days","chapter":9,"marks":1},{"question":"List of accounts which are not operated since last 10 years are required to be reported to RBI within ……….from the date of close of calendar year.","options":["No transaction  for 2 years after the date of last transaction","2 years after the date of opening the account","all above"],"answer":"No transaction  for 2 years after the date of last transaction","chapter":9,"marks":1},{"question":"When account should be considered as inoperative account?","options":["Prevailing as on the date of claim","Savings bank deposit","Contracted","As per negotiation"],"answer":"Savings bank deposit","chapter":9,"marks":1},
  {"question":"When depositor has utilised nomination facility an made valid nomination or where the account was opened with survivorship clause, payment of balance in deposit account to the survivor / nominee of the deceased deposit account holder represents a valid discharge if ……","options":["Submitted the valid documentary evidence","No court order","Made clear to survivor that he is acting as trustee of legal heirs","All above"],"answer":"All above","chapter":10,"marks":1},{"question":"Whether premature termination is allowed in the event of death of the depositor... .......Yes or No","options":["Yes","No"],"answer":"Yes","chapter":10,"marks":1},{"question":"Can penal charges be levied for premature withdrawal of deceased depositors’ deposit? ………Yes or No.","options":["Yes","No"],"answer":"No","chapter":10,"marks":1},{"question":"In the case of NRE deposit when claimants are residents the deposit on maturity should be treated as …………..","options":["NRE Deposit","Resident deposit","all above"],"answer":"Resident deposit","chapter":10,"marks":1},{"question":"Bank should settle the claim and release the payment within …………….days from receiving the claim along with documents.","options":["7","15","21","30"],"answer":"15","chapter":10,"marks":1},
  {"question":"As per the Indian evidence act, presumption of death can be raised only after a lapse of ………..years from the date of person being reported missing.","options":["3","5","7","10"],"answer":"7","chapter":11,"marks":1},{"question":"Claim in respect of a missing person can be settled only if …………presumes that the individual is dead.","options":["Bank","Court","Relatives of depositors","Claimants"],"answer":"Court","chapter":11,"marks":1},
  {"question":"It would be in order for bank to ………. the request of surviving depositor to allow pre-mature withdrawal of deposit in case of joint account in the style either or survivor , provided there is an option included in the contract of deposit to repay before maturity and “either any one or the survivorship “ mandate has been obtained from original depositor.","options":["Accept","Reject","accept/reject"],"answer":"Accept","chapter":12,"marks":1},{"question":"As per the FCRA every association referred in the act , if it is not registered with central government accept any foreign contribution only after obtaining prior approval from …………..","options":["RBI","Ministry of Home affairs","IBA","Finance Ministry"],"answer":"Ministry of Home affairs","chapter":12,"marks":1},{"question":"Branch Managers / managers of the deposit account department at larger branches should monitor operations in new accounts at least for ………….from the date of opening the account.","options":["1 month","3 months","6 months","9 months"],"answer":"6 months","chapter":12,"marks":1},{"question":"Bank should have system of monitoring cash deposit and withdrawals for Rs………and above not only deposit account but also all other accounts like cash credit / overdraft etc.","options":["1 lacs","3 lacs","5 lacs","10 lacs"],"answer":"5 lacs","chapter":12,"marks":1},{"question":"What is the precaution that bank is required to take while thumb / toe impression of sick / old / incapacitated account holder wants to withdraw from his account?","options":["Take witness of 2 independent persons known to bank","Take witness of 2persons known to customer","Any witness of 2 persons who are in the premises of bank","Witness of the bank Manger"],"answer":"Take witness of 2 independent persons known to bank","chapter":12,"marks":1},{"question":"At the time of closure of account , account holder is required to submit one of the most important document called ………………..","options":["Application for closure","Pass Book","All unused Cheque leaves","Any one of the above"],"answer":"All unused Cheque leaves","chapter":12,"marks":1},{"question":"In the event of the death of one of the joint account holder , the right to the deposit proceeds does not automatically devolve on ………………….unless there is survivorship.","options":["Surviving joint deposit account holder","Nominee","Survivor of deceased depositor","Any one of the above"],"answer":"Surviving joint deposit account holder","chapter":12,"marks":1},{"question":"“Banks are permitted to accept deposit under Prize cheat and Money circulation scheme act notified on behalf of state government concerned”………….True or False","options":["True","False"],"answer":"False","chapter":12,"marks":1},{"question":"Banks are……………from paying brokerage on deposits in any form to any individual, firm company, association, institutions or any other persons.","options":["Permitted","Prohibited","none of the above"],"answer":"Prohibited","chapter":12,"marks":1},{"question":"Bank should encourage the opening of joint account on terms such as …………","options":["Either or survivor","Former / later or survivor","Any one or survivor","Any one above"],"answer":"Any one above","chapter":12,"marks":1},
  {"question":"Whether banks are permitted to pay rate of interest higher than that stipulated from time to time by the Reserve Bank of India (Savings and Fixed deposit)?","options":["Permitted","Not permitted","Prohibited"],"answer":"Not permitted","chapter":13,"marks":1},{"question":"No bank may pay interest on …………….other than by sponsor bank to accounts maintained by Regional Rural Banks sponsored by them and on account deceased depositors.","options":["Savings account","Current account","Foxed deposit account","All accounts"],"answer":"Current account","chapter":13,"marks":1},{"question":"“Banks may pay brokerage or gifts to agents / others for deposits placed at Bank”. …True or False","options":["True","False"],"answer":"False","chapter":13,"marks":1},{"question":"No bank should accept interest free deposit other than in ………….or pay compensation indirectly","options":["Current account","Savings account","Term deposit","Composite deposit"],"answer":"Current account","chapter":13,"marks":1},{"question":"“Bank can launch schemes giving prize/ lottery/ free trips to attract deposit”….True or False","options":["True","False"],"answer":"False","chapter":13,"marks":1},{"question":"Banks are permitted to pay commission to ………….to collect door to door deposits under a special scheme","options":["Agents employed","Employees appointed","Any person","Brokers"],"answer":"Agents employed","chapter":13,"marks":1},{"question":"Banks are permitted give inexpensive gifts costing not more than Rs……………..","options":["100","150","200","250"],"answer":"250","chapter":13,"marks":1},
  // {"question":"DICGC Covers…………………….","options":["All commercial Banks","All state , central and primary cooperative banks","All above","Only private sector banks"],"answer":"All above","chapter":14,"marks":1},{"question":"In the event of Bank failure, DICGC protects …………..that are payable in India","options":["Bank Deposits","Customer Deposits","Bank Loan","Customer Loan"],"answer":"Bank Deposits","chapter":14,"marks":1},{"question":"What types of deposits are covered under DICGC?","options":["Savings and current","Fixed Deposit","Recurring Deposit","All above"],"answer":"All above","chapter":14,"marks":1},{"question":"What types of deposits are not covered under DICGC?","options":["Deposits of Foreign Government","Deposits of Central / state government","Interbank/deposits received from outside India","All above"],"answer":"All above","chapter":14,"marks":1},{"question":"Presently , deposits of each depositor in bank is insured up to maximum of Rs……………………for both principal and interest amount held by him in the same right and in the same capacity as on the date of liquidation / cancellation of Bank’s licence  or the date on which the scheme of amalgamation / merger reconstruction comes in to force.","options":["1,00,000","3,00,000","5,00,000","10,00,000"],"answer":"1,00,000","chapter":14,"marks":1},{"question":"If there are deposits with more than one bank , deposit insurance coverage limit is applied ………… to the deposits in each bank.","options":["Together","Separately","Bank wise","Name wise"],"answer":"Separately","chapter":14,"marks":1},{"question":"If bank is required to recover the dues from the amount of deposit , in that case whether deposit insurance is available original deposit amount or netting off of amount?","options":["Original deposit amount","Netting off amount after recovery of dues.","none of the above"],"answer":"Netting off amount after recovery of dues.","chapter":14,"marks":1},{"question":"Who bears the cost of premium of Deposit insurance?","options":["Bank","Individual depositor","none of the above"],"answer":"Bank","chapter":14,"marks":1},{"question":"Who bears the cost of premium of Deposit insurance?","options":["If bank goes in to liquidation","Within 2 months from the date of claim through liquidator","All above","When demanded by depositor"],"answer":"All above","chapter":14,"marks":1},{"question":"When DICGC pays?","options":["Optional","Compulsory","none of the above"],"answer":"Compulsory","chapter":14,"marks":1},
  {"question":"What do you mean by Retail Loan?","options":["Loan given to companies","Loans given to institutions","Loans given to individuals","All above"],"answer":"Loans given to individuals","chapter":15,"marks":1},{"question":"What is the purpose of retails loan?","options":["To help the companies","To assist to the institutions during difficult period","To meet the personal need","To invest in the business"],"answer":"To meet the personal need","chapter":15,"marks":1},{"question":"What is secured loan?","options":["Loan given on security of relatives","Loan given on recommendation of Bank employees","Loan given against security of some assets","All above"],"answer":"Loan given against security of some assets","chapter":15,"marks":1},{"question":"What is the security offered to Home Loan?","options":["Mortgage","Hypothecation","Pledge","Any one above"],"answer":"Mortgage","chapter":15,"marks":1},{"question":"What is the security offered to Car Loan?","options":["Mortgage","Hypothecation","Pledge","Any one above"],"answer":"Hypothecation","chapter":15,"marks":1},{"question":"What is the security offered to Fixed Deposit?","options":["Mortgage","Hypothecation","Pledge","Any one above"],"answer":"Pledge","chapter":15,"marks":1},{"question":"Secured retail loans are……………………….","options":["Education Loan / loan to professional / self employed","Loan against shares","Home Loan / Car Loan","All above"],"answer":"All above","chapter":15,"marks":1},
  // {"question":"Personal loans are granted to persons having minimum age of …………….who have disposable income to repay the loan.","options":["18 years","21 years","18/21 years","25 years"],"answer":"18/21 years","chapter":16,"marks":1},{"question":"Personal loans are not advanced to individuals who are…………….","options":["Not employed","Likely to retire in 1or 2 years","Likely to retire in 5 years","None of the above"],"answer":"Likely to retire in 1or 2 years","chapter":16,"marks":1},{"question":"Personal loans are not advanced to individuals who are…………….","options":["He should be permanent employee","Confirmed in the services minimum 1 year","None of the above","All above"],"answer":"All above","chapter":16,"marks":1},{"question":"What are the criteria to grant a personal loan to employee of the organisation?","options":["Stable income","In the business for minimum 1 year","Both above","Should have place of business"],"answer":"Both above","chapter":16,"marks":1},{"question":"Self employed person should have ………to grant the personal loan.","options":["Agent is doing the insurance business for the last 5 years","Agent is doing the business for 3 years","Agent is doing the business for 1 year","Any one above"],"answer":"Agent is doing the insurance business for the last 5 years","chapter":16,"marks":1},
  {"question":"Purchase of washing machine, dish washer, mobile phones, cooking range etc are covered under ……………………….","options":["Personal loan","Consumer durable loan","Business loan","Any above"],"answer":"Consumer durable loan","chapter":17,"marks":1},{"question":"Consumer durable loans are normally less than…………………","options":["Rs. 5000","Rs. 100,000","Rs.500,000","Rs. 10,00,000"],"answer":"Rs. 100,000","chapter":17,"marks":1},{"question":"Period of consumer durable loan is ………………..","options":["12 months","24 months","36 months","12-36 months"],"answer":"12-36 months","chapter":17,"marks":1},{"question":"Is there any margin requirement for consumer durable loan?.............Yes or no","options":["Yes","No"],"answer":"Yes","chapter":17,"marks":1},{"question":"Quantum of consumer durable loan is ………………………..","options":["100%","90%","75%","50%"],"answer":"90%","chapter":17,"marks":1},
  {"question":"Loans granted to doctors, chartered accountants, practicing company secretaries etc for purchase of office equipments are classified under…………………","options":["Personal loan","Consumer durable loan","Professional and self employed person loan","Any one above"],"answer":"Professional and self employed person loan","chapter":18,"marks":1},{"question":"Only the professional and self employed whose borrowing do not exceed Rs…………..of which not more than Rs.2 lakh are of the working capital requirement should be covered under loans to professional and self employed.","options":["25 lakh","10 lakh","5 lakh","None above"],"answer":"10 lakh","chapter":18,"marks":1},{"question":"For the professionally qualified medical practitioners , setting up of practices in semi urban and rural areas  the borrowing limit should not exceed …………..with a sub ceiling of Rs. 3 lakh for working capital requirement.","options":["25 lakh","15 lakh","10 lakh","5 lakh"],"answer":"15 lakh","chapter":18,"marks":1},{"question":"What is the rate of interest for loans granted to professionals?","options":["10%","12%","13%","Differ from bank to bank"],"answer":"Differ from bank to bank","chapter":18,"marks":1},{"question":"The maximum period of loan granted to professionals and self employed is …………….","options":["24 months","36 months","36 to 60 months","36 to 60 months"],"answer":"36 to 60 months","chapter":18,"marks":1},
  {"question":"Basic criteria to grant the education loan is ………………….","options":["To help to get the education","To help the student’s family","Employability","To help only meritorious students"],"answer":"Employability","chapter":19,"marks":1},{"question":"“Education loans are welfare measures to enable poor students to pursue higher studies with the assistance with loan facilities provided by Banks”…………..True or False","options":["True","False"],"answer":"True","chapter":19,"marks":1},{"question":"Whether study tour, project work, thesis etc are covered while computing the amount required under the education loan?...............Yes or no","options":["Yes","No"],"answer":"Yes","chapter":19,"marks":1},{"question":"What is the quantum of finance for studies abroad?","options":["Rs. 10 lacs","Rs. 20 lacs","Rs. 25 lacs","Rs. 50 lacs"],"answer":"Rs. 20 lacs","chapter":19,"marks":1},{"question":"What is the margin requirement for education loan up to Rs. 4 lacs?","options":["5%","10%","25%","No margin"],"answer":"No margin","chapter":19,"marks":1},{"question":"What is the security prescribed for education loan above Rs. 7.5 lacs?","options":["Parents to be joint borrower","Tangible security","Any one above","Both above a & b"],"answer":"Both above a & b","chapter":19,"marks":1},{"question":"Whether the loan documents are to be executed by student only or parents are also required to join the execution of loan documentation?","options":["Student alone","Parents with student jointly","Parents alone"],"answer":"Parents with student jointly","chapter":19,"marks":1},{"question":"What is the period within which sanction / rejection should be communicated to student / parent?","options":["7 days","15 days","21 days","30 days"],"answer":"15 days","chapter":19,"marks":1},{"question":"What is the rate of interest charged on education loan?","options":["Simple interest during study period","Simple interest during study period up to commencement of repayment","Simple interest during study period up to commencement of repayment linked to base rate","As per the base rate for entire tenure of loan"],"answer":"Simple interest during study period up to commencement of repayment linked to base rate","chapter":19,"marks":1},{"question":"Whether any insurance is required for education loan granted?","options":["Life insurance on the life of the student","Credit insurance on loan granted","Life insurance on the life of the parents"],"answer":"Life insurance on the life of the student","chapter":19,"marks":1},
  {"question":"If student has secured the admission in courses run or supported by ministry or organisation or government supported national / state skill Development Corporation leading to certificate / diploma / degree courses what kind of loan is granted by the banks?","options":["Vocational educational and training loan","Normal education loan","Professional loan","Consumer loan"],"answer":"Vocational educational and training loan","chapter":20,"marks":1},{"question":"What is minimum age for granting loan for vocational education and training?","options":["18 years","21 years","25 years","No specific age"],"answer":"No specific age","chapter":20,"marks":1},{"question":"Banks may at their discretion , consider limit up to Rs. 75,000 for vocational courses up to 1 year and limit up to ……………with duration above 1 year for specific courses offered by reputed institutions.","options":["Rs. 1 lakh","Rs. 2 lakh","Rs. 3 lakh","Rs. 5 lakh"],"answer":"Rs. 2 lakh","chapter":20,"marks":1},{"question":"What are the courses considered for granting the loan for vocational courses?","options":["Tuition / course fees/ caution deposit","Examination / library fee / purchase of books","Other reasonable expenses for course","All above"],"answer":"All above","chapter":20,"marks":1},{"question":"What is margin requirement for loan under vocational education and training?","options":["5%","10%","20%","No margin"],"answer":"No margin","chapter":20,"marks":1},{"question":"What is security / collateral required to avail the loan for training?","options":["LI Policy","Other tangible security","Bank deposit certificate","No security"],"answer":"No security","chapter":20,"marks":1},{"question":"Up on completion of training what would be moratorium period generally offered by banks for course duration above 1 year after completion of training?","options":["12 months","9 months","6 months","3 months"],"answer":"12 months","chapter":20,"marks":1},{"question":"What is the repayment period for vocational loan after moratorium period for loans between Rs. 50,000 to Rs. 1 lakh?","options":["Up to 2 years","2 to 5 years","3 to 7 years","10 years"],"answer":"2 to 5 years","chapter":20,"marks":1},

  {"question":"What is the maximum age for granting the vehicle loan by banks?","options":["50 years","55 years","58 years","60 years"],"answer":"60 years","chapter":21,"marks":1},{"question":"Usually the vehicle loan is granted up to ……of the cost / invoice value of the vehicle including accessories and registration expenses in case of new vehicles.","options":["70%","75%","80%","90%"],"answer":"80%","chapter":21,"marks":1},{"question":"The entire vehicle loan with interest is required to be paid in …………..equated monthly instalments.","options":["24","36","36 to 60","60"],"answer":"36 to 60","chapter":21,"marks":1},{"question":"What is the security for vehicle loan?","options":["Lien","Pledge","Hypothecation","Other tangible securities"],"answer":"Hypothecation","chapter":21,"marks":1},{"question":"Hire purchase is to be noted in the registration book issued by ………….","options":["Bank","RTO","Seller","Vendor"],"answer":"RTO","chapter":21,"marks":1},{"question":"Whether insurance is requirement is mandatory?...............Yes or No","options":["Yes","No"],"answer":"Yes","chapter":21,"marks":1},{"question":"If no repayment is made by the borrower, what is the last remedy to the bank?","options":["To call the borrower and reschedule the repayment schedule","Claim under insurance","Seize the vehicle","Any one above"],"answer":"Seize the vehicle","chapter":21,"marks":1},
  {"question":"What could be possible purpose of granting loan against shares and debentures?","options":["Personal need","To meet the contingency","For purchase of security in secondary market","All above"],"answer":"All above","chapter":22,"marks":1},{"question":"What the limit up to which loan under ESOPS can be granted by banks to staff / employees of the company?","options":["90 %","90% or Rs 20 lakh  whichever is less","100% or Rs. 25 lakh whichever is less","100%"],"answer":"90% or Rs 20 lakh  whichever is less","chapter":22,"marks":1},{"question":"Loan against the security of shares / debentures and PSU bonds in physical form is granted up to a maximum of Rs……………..","options":["10 lakh","15 lakh","20 lakh","25lakh"],"answer":"10 lakh","chapter":22,"marks":1},{"question":"Whether loan against the units of all mutual funds can be granted by the banks?","options":["Granted only against the units listed on stock exchange","Non listed mutual fund units","Any units","Specified units"],"answer":"Granted only against the units listed on stock exchange","chapter":22,"marks":1},{"question":"What are the criteria for granting the loan against mutual fund?","options":["NAV","Market value","NAV or Market value whichever is less","Face value"],"answer":"NAV or Market value whichever is less","chapter":22,"marks":1},{"question":"Banks cannot grant the loans to ………………..against the security of shares and debentures.","options":["Minors","Trusts and endowments","Corporate","Individuals beyond 60 years"],"answer":"Trusts and endowments","chapter":22,"marks":1},
  {"question":"What is indirect housing finance?","options":["Finance granted to housing finance institutions / housing board","Finance to purchase plot","Finance to construct the building","All above"],"answer":"All above","chapter":23,"marks":1},{"question":"Can housing loan be granted for purchase of constructed property / built up property?.................Yes or No","options":["Yes","No"],"answer":"Yes","chapter":23,"marks":1},{"question":"Housing loans are not normally extended to individuals who are above ………….years","options":["55","58","60"],"answer":"58","chapter":23,"marks":1},{"question":"The maximum quantum of loan depend up on bank and could vary from Rs. 10 lakh to …………….or more","options":["50 lakh","1 Cr","2 Cr","5 Cr"],"answer":"2 Cr","chapter":23,"marks":1},{"question":"The loan amount for repairs would normally be less –usually around Rs……..","options":["1 lakh","3 lakh","5 lakh","10 lakh"],"answer":"10 lakh","chapter":23,"marks":1},{"question":"The maximum tenor of the loan should not exceed………………","options":["10 years","15 years","25 years","15-25 years"],"answer":"15-25 years","chapter":23,"marks":1},{"question":"What is the security to housing loan that is normally taken by Banks?","options":["Mortgage","Guarantee","Both above","Any tangible security"],"answer":"Both above","chapter":23,"marks":1},
  {"question":"What is reverse mortgage?","options":["Designed for Senior citizens","Conversion of home property in to income channel","Both above","Only b"],"answer":"Both above","chapter":24,"marks":1},{"question":"What is the age requirement to avail the loan under reverse merger?","options":["55 years","58 Years","60 years","65 years"],"answer":"60 years","chapter":24,"marks":1},{"question":"The maximum amount of Loan that can be granted by Bank under reverse merger is ………….3.\tThe maximum amount of Loan that can be granted by Bank under reverse merger is ………….","options":["10 lakh","25 lakh","50 lakh","1 crore"],"answer":"1 crore","chapter":24,"marks":1},{"question":"Who pays loan taken under reverse mortgage?","options":["Borrower","Last surviving borrower","Sell of home by borrower","Any one"],"answer":"Any one","chapter":24,"marks":1},{"question":"What is normal period of repayment of loan under Reverse merger?","options":["5 Years","10 Years","15 Years","20 Years"],"answer":"15 Years","chapter":24,"marks":1},
  {"question":"What are the principles of sound lending?","options":["Purpose and ability to repay loan","Term of the Loan","Integrity of the borrower","All above"],"answer":"All above","chapter":25,"marks":1},{"question":"What are the characteristic features of Retail credit analysis?","options":["Loans to individual","No collaterals","Gut feeling that individual will repay","All above"],"answer":"All above","chapter":25,"marks":1},{"question":"What are the documents required to check?","options":["Identity/ pan card","Bank statement","Address","All above"],"answer":"All above","chapter":25,"marks":1},{"question":"What are the safety indicators in retail loan?","options":["House owner","Adequate resources","Both above","Only b"],"answer":"Both above","chapter":25,"marks":1},{"question":"“The class of the society the person comes from has an effect on the Risk”…..True or False","options":["True","False"],"answer":"True","chapter":25,"marks":1},
  {"question":"Banks and Financial institutions should ensure that all information relating to charges / fees for processing are invariably disclosed to borrower ………………..","options":["In loan application","Explained while granting loan","To ask to read and sign","Any one above"],"answer":"In loan application","chapter":26,"marks":1},{"question":"Lender should not use ………..and ……stipulations as substitute for due diligence on credit worthiness of borrowers.","options":["Name and address","Interest and margin","Margin and security","Security and repayment"],"answer":"Margin and security","chapter":26,"marks":1},{"question":"Post disbursement supervision by lenders in respect of loan up to Rs…………should be constructive with a view to taking care of any “lender related” genuine difficulty  that the borrower may face.","options":["1 lakh","2 lakh","3 lakh","5 lakh"],"answer":"2 lakh","chapter":26,"marks":1},{"question":"A consolidated review of policy on loan should be submitted to ………………….by Controlling offices of the bank.","options":["Top Management","Executive Director","Board of Directors","MD and CEO"],"answer":"Board of Directors","chapter":26,"marks":1},{"question":"Decision on request for transfer of loan should be conveyed within ………..days from the date of receipt of request.","options":["7","14","21","30"],"answer":"21","chapter":26,"marks":1},
  {"question":"What is the duty of recovery agent?","options":["To recover the loans","To recover retail loan","To recover Personal loans","To recover home loan"],"answer":"To recover retail loan","chapter":27,"marks":1},{"question":"Who issued the guidelines for appointing recovery agent?","options":["Concerned Bank","IBA","Reserve Bank of India","As per practices"],"answer":"Reserve Bank of India","chapter":27,"marks":1},{"question":"What should be due diligence process consists of?","options":["Verification of antecedents of their employees","Police verification of recovery agent","Agent to carry notice of recovery","All above"],"answer":"All above","chapter":27,"marks":1},{"question":"What recovery agent should carry with him while going for recovery?","options":["Notice and authorisation letter","Bamboo stick","Gun","Any one above"],"answer":"Notice and authorisation letter","chapter":27,"marks":1},{"question":"Who conducts certificate course under training to recovery agents?","options":["Individual banks","Reserve Bank","IBA","Indian institute of Banking and Finance"],"answer":"Indian institute of Banking and Finance","chapter":27,"marks":1},{"question":"As per the court judgement bank should not …………..for recovery of loan.","options":["Appoint musclemen","Grant loans who cannot repay","Grant Loan to Jobless persons","Grant loan to thieves"],"answer":"Appoint musclemen","chapter":27,"marks":1},{"question":"What is the suggestion of Reserve Bank of India as per the court direction to recover the retail loans grated for less than 10 lakh?","options":["Go for court settlement","Refer to Lok Adalat organised by court","File case against borrower","Send recovery agent to borrower till recovery happens"],"answer":"Refer to Lok Adalat organised by court","chapter":27,"marks":1},
  {"question":"What do you call the money pooled for the purpose of investment in fund?","options":["Investment","Corpus","Loan","Deposit"],"answer":"Corpus","chapter":28,"marks":1},{"question":"Mutual fund investment gains are distributed to investor by way of …………….or through increase in value of the units or allocation of additional units.","options":["Interest","Dividend","Dividend/Intrest"],"answer":"Dividend","chapter":28,"marks":1},{"question":"Mutual funds are ………………..","options":["Para bank","Financial Institutions","Financial intermediary","NGO"],"answer":"Financial intermediary","chapter":28,"marks":1},{"question":"In ……………subscription to and redemption from mutual fund scheme are open all through the year.","options":["Close ended scheme","Open ended scheme","Income scheme","Gift fund"],"answer":"Open ended scheme","chapter":28,"marks":1},{"question":"Units with fixed maturity period from 3 to 15 years are issued under…………..","options":["Open ended scheme","Close ended scheme","Growth or equity fund","Income scheme"],"answer":"Close ended scheme","chapter":28,"marks":1},{"question":"What is the objective of growth fund?","options":["Investment on long term basis","Provide maximum returns","Attract investment","Alternate to share market"],"answer":"Provide maximum returns","chapter":28,"marks":1},{"question":"Funds that invest in both shares and fixed income securities in the proportion indicated in their offer documents is called as ………………….","options":["Gift Fund","Income fund","Balanced Fund","Growth fund"],"answer":"Balanced Fund","chapter":28,"marks":1},{"question":"A fund whose portfolio is built around a particular sector or theme is called as…….","options":["Sector fund","Gilt fund","Bond Fund","Income Fund"],"answer":"Sector fund","chapter":28,"marks":1},{"question":"Gilt fund invest much of their corpus in sovereign securities issued by …………..","options":["State government","Central government","Non Government funds","Government PF"],"answer":"Central government","chapter":28,"marks":1},{"question":"Money that is pooled together by a large number of investors who give their money to a fund Manager to invest in stock and /or bonds is called ………………….","options":["Share market investment","Money market investment","Mutual fund investment","Investment in bonds"],"answer":"Mutual fund investment","chapter":28,"marks":1},
  {"question":"A method by which a person can get his physical share certificate converted in to electronic form is called ………………….","options":["Demat","Dematerialisation","Transfer","Sale"],"answer":"Dematerialisation","chapter":29,"marks":1},{"question":"A…………is an organisation like central bank where at the request of shareholder his \nSecurities are held in electronic form.","options":["Share market","Mutual Fund","Depository","OTC"],"answer":"Depository","chapter":29,"marks":1},{"question":"What are NSDL and CSDL?","options":["Share market","Stock Depository","Trading Houses","Settlement Houses"],"answer":"Stock Depository","chapter":29,"marks":1},{"question":"Depository system operates in the line of ……………..System","options":["Stock Exchange","Banking","Mutual Funds","OTC"],"answer":"Banking","chapter":29,"marks":1},{"question":"Whether it is possible to pledge and hypothecate the securities under dematerialisation? …….Yes or No.","options":["Yes","No"],"answer":"Yes","chapter":29,"marks":1},
  {"question":"Bancassurance in its simplest form is a term which is coined to denote combination of …………..within the same organisation.","options":["Business and insurance","Business insurance","Banking and insurance","Banking insurance"],"answer":"Banking and insurance","chapter":30,"marks":1},{"question":"The customer sees bancassurance as a bonanza in terms of …………………..","options":["Reduced Price","High quality product and delivery at doorsteps","Both above","Any one above"],"answer":"Both above","chapter":30,"marks":1},{"question":"What is the reason for offering the Bancassurance by Banks?","options":["Non Fund based fee income","Customer approach","Lower cost and marketing capabilities","All above"],"answer":"All above","chapter":30,"marks":1},
  {"question":"Bank Draft is ………………..","options":["Order drawn by an office  of Bank  up on another office of same Bank","Instructing other office to pay specified sum to named person","Both above","Any one above"],"answer":"Both above","chapter":31,"marks":1},{"question":"Bank draft is also called as ………..","options":["Cheque","Pay order","Bill of Exchange","Promissory note"],"answer":"Bill of Exchange","chapter":31,"marks":1},{"question":"Validity of the draft is …………………..from the date of issue.","options":["3 months","6 months","9 months","1 year"],"answer":"6 months","chapter":31,"marks":1},{"question":"What documents adequate identification for encashment of draft?","options":["Passport","Postal identification card","Any one above","None of the above"],"answer":"Any one above","chapter":31,"marks":1},{"question":"Under what circumstances duplicate draft can be issued?","options":["Draft is lost","Draft Mutilated","None of the above","Both A & B"],"answer":"Both A & B","chapter":31,"marks":1},{"question":"What is the amount beyond which indemnity is required to provide by purchaser to issue duplicate draft?","options":["Rs. 1000","Rs. 5000","Rs. 10000","Rs. 50000"],"answer":"Rs. 5000","chapter":31,"marks":1},{"question":"What is the period within which duplicate draft should be issued by Bank?","options":["7 days","15 days","3 weeks","1 month"],"answer":"15 days","chapter":31,"marks":1},{"question":"Refusal to draft is tantamount to stating the bank is bankrupt.","options":["True","False"],"answer":"True","chapter":31,"marks":1},
  {"question":"A………….is a cheque drawn by the bank on itself to pay the named person  a sum certain in money.","options":["Draft","Pay order","Bill of exchange","Promissory note"],"answer":"Pay order","chapter":32,"marks":1},{"question":"Under what circumstances pay order is issued?","options":["If beneficiary does not maintain account","If purchaser not having bank account","Any one above","All above"],"answer":"If beneficiary does not maintain account","chapter":32,"marks":1},{"question":"Is pay order is included in negotiable instrument act?...........Yes or No","options":["Yes","No"],"answer":"No","chapter":32,"marks":1},
  {"question":"Where you can purchase travellers cheques?","options":["Bank / post office","Travel agent","Forex Bureaux","All above"],"answer":"All above","chapter":33,"marks":1},{"question":"How traveller’s cheques are issued?","options":["At face value","At price determined by agent","As per customers wish","Fixed market price"],"answer":"At face value","chapter":33,"marks":1},{"question":"On purchasing the traveller’s cheque ………..is required to sign the cheques the cheques in the presence of issuer.","options":["Seller","Purchaser","Bank","Any one above"],"answer":"Purchaser","chapter":33,"marks":1},{"question":"“There is no expiry date for travellers cheques and they never go stale”…….True or False","options":["True","False"],"answer":"True","chapter":33,"marks":1},{"question":"What are the major benefits of traveller’s cheque?","options":["Accepted world wide","No expiry date","Safer than money","All above"],"answer":"All above","chapter":33,"marks":1},
  {"question":"What is clearing of cheques?","options":["To clear the pending cheques","To remove the written contents of the cheque","Arrangement to exchange the cheques drawn on other banks","To post all the cheques received"],"answer":"Arrangement to exchange the cheques drawn on other banks","chapter":34,"marks":1},{"question":"What is the place called, where banks that are members meet to handover the cheques?","options":["Bank","Head office of bank","Reserve Bank","Clearing House"],"answer":"Clearing House","chapter":34,"marks":1},{"question":"Who manages the clearing house?","options":["Individual Banks","Reserve Bank","IBA"],"answer":"Reserve Bank","chapter":34,"marks":1},{"question":"The instruments presented at a clearing house are…………..","options":["Cheques and drafts","Pay order","Both above","Bill of Exchange"],"answer":"Both above","chapter":34,"marks":1},{"question":"What are the types of clearing?","options":["Outward clearing","inward clearing","both above","Special clearing"],"answer":"both above","chapter":34,"marks":1},{"question":"What is local clearing?","options":["Cheques drawn locally","Cheques drawn by  banks near to clearing house","Cheques drawn by outstation banks","Cheques drawn by outstation branches","Both above."],"answer":"Cheques drawn locally","chapter":34,"marks":1},{"question":"If cheques deposited by customer are lost in transit …………….must pay the value of the cheques lost.","options":["Bank","Drawer","Presenting bank","Paying bank"],"answer":"Bank","chapter":34,"marks":1},{"question":"Foreign cheque payment is usually released after……..working days from the value date and rate used would be the rate applicable on the date of credit to the customer’s account.","options":["7 days","15 days","21 days","30 days"],"answer":"21 days","chapter":34,"marks":1},{"question":"Time frame on cheque clearing drawn on state capital/major cities / other locations should be ……………days respectively","options":["1/3/5","3/5/7","7/10/14","7/10/21"],"answer":"7/10/14","chapter":34,"marks":1},{"question":"Local cheques should be processed ………..working day and customers should be able to draw T+1 OR T+2 working days","options":["T","T+1","T+2","T+ 3"],"answer":"T+1","chapter":34,"marks":1},
  {"question":"Truncation is the process of ………….the flow of physical cheque issued by a drawer to the drawee branch.","options":["Allowing","Stopping","Holding","Clearing"],"answer":"Stopping","chapter":35,"marks":1},{"question":"Settlement under cheque truncation is based on ……………….","options":["Electronic data","Images","Both above","None of the above"],"answer":"Both above","chapter":35,"marks":1},{"question":"How the image and data transmission over the network is secure?","options":["Usage top IT security","Usage of PKI","Secured image","Clear transmission"],"answer":"Usage of PKI","chapter":35,"marks":1},{"question":"What type of cheques can be presented in the CTS?","options":["All local cheques","Only high value cheques","Only MICR cheques","Non MICR cheques"],"answer":"All local cheques","chapter":35,"marks":1},{"question":"How does cheque truncation works?","options":["capturing the image of cheque through scanner at local branch","capturing image at central location","capturing image at clearing house","all above"],"answer":"capturing the image of cheque through scanner at local branch","chapter":35,"marks":1},{"question":"Who specified the image standard in truncation of cheques?","options":["Individual Bank","Reserve Bank","Indian Bank association","Clearing house"],"answer":"Reserve Bank","chapter":35,"marks":1},{"question":"Verification of genuineness of the cheque based on visible features is the legal risk carried out by ……………………","options":["Paying bank","Collecting bank","Clearing house","Settlement Bank"],"answer":"Collecting bank","chapter":35,"marks":1},
  {"question":"What is electronic clearing services?","options":["Sending cheques image","Sending payment instructions electronically","Clearing instrument is required","Only for low volume instruments"],"answer":"Sending payment instructions electronically","chapter":36,"marks":1},{"question":"Who processes the transactions under ECS?","options":["Clearing cell","Reserve Bank","Respective Bank","National clearing Cell"],"answer":"National clearing Cell","chapter":36,"marks":1},{"question":"Normally, what are charges levied to ECS debit by sponsor bank?","options":["Minimum","Negligible","De-regulated","No charges"],"answer":"De-regulated","chapter":36,"marks":1},{"question":"One of the major benefits of using ECS is by corporate is …………….","options":["Loss of instrument and fraudulent encashment eliminated","Time saving","Less employee","Easy reconciliation"],"answer":"Loss of instrument and fraudulent encashment eliminated","chapter":36,"marks":1},{"question":"What is benefit to the beneficiary under ECS payment?","options":["Payment on due date","Faster processing","Better cash management","All above"],"answer":"All above","chapter":36,"marks":1},
  {"question":"Who will hold liable to pay penal interest at the rate of prevailing bank rate plus 2% from the due date of credit till the date of actual credit for any delayed credit to beneficiary account?","options":["Originating Bank","Paying bank","Both the above"],"answer":"Paying bank","chapter":37,"marks":1},{"question":"Is there any stipulation for on the minimum number of transactions to be put through, through NECS?............Yes or No","options":["Yes","No"],"answer":"No","chapter":37,"marks":1},{"question":"Who processes the input data submitted under NECS?","options":["Clearing House","Respective Bank","Reserve Bank","Sponsor Bank"],"answer":"Clearing House","chapter":37,"marks":1},{"question":"………….Provides the settlement service by way of crediting / debiting the accounts of destination Banks and sponsor bank in its books on the basis of settlement advised by the clearing house.","options":["Destination Bank","Sponsor Bank","Settlement agency","Clearing House"],"answer":"Settlement agency","chapter":37,"marks":1},{"question":"The institutions desirous to avail of NECS facility have to get themselves registered with …………….","options":["Reserve Bank","Clearing House","Sponsor bank","Settlement bank"],"answer":"Clearing House","chapter":37,"marks":1},
  {"question":"Speed clearing refers to collection of …………Cheques through the local clearing","options":["Local","Outstation","Foreign","Any kind of"],"answer":"Outstation","chapter":38,"marks":1},{"question":"Speed clearing aims to reduce the time taken for …………..","options":["7/10/14","2/3/5","1/2/3","7/10/15"],"answer":"7/10/14","chapter":38,"marks":1},{"question":"Cheques having transaction code ……………..drawn on CBS –enabled bank  branches at the local centre","options":["10","11","13","Any one above"],"answer":"Any one above","chapter":38,"marks":1},{"question":"Out station cheques under speed clearing will be paid within ………hours","options":["12","24","36","48"],"answer":"48","chapter":38,"marks":1},{"question":"What are the charges permitted to levy for cheques processing under speed clearing?","options":["Rs. 50","Rs.100","Rs 150","Rs 200"],"answer":"Rs 150","chapter":38,"marks":1},
  {"question":"The ACU is System for clearing payments among the member countries on a ………..Basis.","options":["Unilateral","Bilateral","Multilateral","Direct"],"answer":"Multilateral","chapter":39,"marks":1},{"question":"Authorised dealer can open …………account in the name of Banks  in all member countries including Pakistan without the prior approval of Reserve Bank of India","options":["Current","Savings","ACU Dollar","Normal"],"answer":"ACU Dollar","chapter":39,"marks":1},{"question":"Under ACU most of the transactions are settled directly through the accounts maintained by authorised dealers with Banks in other countries in the other …………countries and vice versa.","options":["Neighbouring","Any","Participating","World wide"],"answer":"Participating","chapter":39,"marks":1},{"question":"Authorised Dealer should ensure that at all the times that balances maintained in ……..account are commensurate with the requirement of their normal exchange business and funds rendered surplus should be repatriated to India regularly.","options":["Dollar Nostro","Rupee Vostro","ACU Dollar","Any one above"],"answer":"ACU Dollar","chapter":39,"marks":1},{"question":"Settlement under ACU Dollar account happens through ……………….in USD from to AD for the purpose of funding.","options":["Reserve Bank of India","State Bank of India","Any Bank","Bank maintaining account"],"answer":"Reserve Bank of India","chapter":39,"marks":1},{"question":"Payments which are not eligible to settle through ACU are………………","options":["Nepal and India","Capital account transactions","Both above","None of the above"],"answer":"Both above","chapter":39,"marks":1},{"question":"Transactions that are eligible to make through ACU are payments ……………","options":["From resident of  territory of one participant to another","Export / import transactions","Payment in compliance with ACM Memorandum","All above"],"answer":"All above","chapter":39,"marks":1},
  {"question":"What is standing instructions?","options":["Specific payment","To specific person / organisation","On specific date","All above"],"answer":"All above","chapter":40,"marks":1},{"question":"Can customer stop the payment any time and instruct the bank for the standing instructions given?.....................Yes or No","options":["Yes","No"],"answer":"Yes","chapter":40,"marks":1},{"question":"If there is no balance as on particular date in the account , can bank execute the standing instructions?................Yes or No","options":["Yes","No"],"answer":"No","chapter":40,"marks":1},{"question":"Standing instruction can be noted by bank for which type of account?","options":["Savings account","Current account","Both above","Any account"],"answer":"Both above","chapter":40,"marks":1},{"question":"Is there any charges are levied by bank for accepting the standing instructions?….Yes or No","options":["Yes","No"],"answer":"No","chapter":40,"marks":1},
  {"question":"What is mail transfer?","options":["Remitting money from one place to another through bank","Bank sends advice by mail to its branch","Receiving bank sends advice of payment","All above"],"answer":"All above","chapter":41,"marks":1},{"question":"Is the bank charges for sending the money transfer?..........Yes or No","options":["Yes","No"],"answer":"Yes","chapter":41,"marks":1},{"question":"Mail transfer is an arrangement between two offices of  branch or two banks and is ………….payment order.","options":["Negotiable","Non negotiable","Order","Request"],"answer":"Non negotiable","chapter":41,"marks":1},{"question":"What is wire transfer?","options":["Transfer of funds by telegram / telex","Within and across the national boundaries","No restriction of currency","All above"],"answer":"All above","chapter":41,"marks":1},{"question":"Who is ordering bank in wire transfer?","options":["Originated the transaction","Middle bank","Receiving bank","Any bank involved in transaction"],"answer":"Originated the transaction","chapter":41,"marks":1},
  {"question":"System of MTSS is tie-up between reputed money transfer companies abroad known as …………….","options":["Overseas principle","Remittance company","Money transfer company","Remitting bank"],"answer":"Overseas principle","chapter":42,"marks":1},{"question":"The entity that pays the money to beneficiary in India is called as ……………","options":["Principle","Agent","Bank","Money changers"],"answer":"Agent","chapter":42,"marks":1},{"question":"Whether Indian agent is permitted to  remit any amount to overseas principle under MTSS?............Yes or No","options":["Yes","No"],"answer":"No","chapter":42,"marks":1},{"question":"What is the cap place on the individual remittance under the MTSS scheme?","options":["USD 1000","USD 2500","USD 3000","USD 5000"],"answer":"USD 2500","chapter":42,"marks":1},{"question":"Only………..remittances can be received by single individual beneficiary under the MTSS scheme during the calendar year.","options":["12","25","30","50"],"answer":"30","chapter":42,"marks":1},{"question":"Can Indian agent appoints subagent? ……………….Yes or No","options":["Yes","No"],"answer":"Yes","chapter":42,"marks":1},{"question":"Who is responsible for due diligence on sub agent appointed in India?","options":["Indian Agent","Overseas principle","Both a & b","Reserve Bank"],"answer":"Both a & b","chapter":42,"marks":1},
  {"question":"What is advantage of RTGS?","options":["Minimises Risk","Centrepiece of an integrated payment system","A & B","Any one"],"answer":"A & B","chapter":43,"marks":1},{"question":"RTGS is the system where transfer of money takes place from …………….on real time and on gross basis.","options":["Bank to customer","Bank to Bank","Customer to Bank","Between customers"],"answer":"Bank to Bank","chapter":43,"marks":1},{"question":"Under RTGS money transfer takes place in the books of …………., payment is final and irrevocable","options":["Remitting bank","Paying Bank","Reserve Bank","Settlement Bank"],"answer":"Reserve Bank","chapter":43,"marks":1},{"question":"What is the minimum amount prescribed to transfer the funds through RTGS?","options":["1 Lakh","5 lakh","7 lakh","10 lakh"],"answer":"1 Lakh","chapter":43,"marks":1},{"question":"RTGS system is maintained and operated by……………….","options":["Respective Banks","Reserve Bank","IBA","PSU banks"],"answer":"Reserve Bank","chapter":43,"marks":1},{"question":"Through RTGS beneficiary account is credited within ……..hours after receiving the funds transfer message.","options":["1 hour","2 hours","12 hours","24 hours"],"answer":"2 hours","chapter":43,"marks":1},{"question":"What are the transactions types handled through RTGS?","options":["Inter institutional transfers","Customer transfers","Own account transfer","All above"],"answer":"All above","chapter":43,"marks":1},
  {"question":"The  scheme introduced by RBI  to help banks offering their customers money transfer service from account to account of any bank branch to any other bank branch is called as ………","options":["EFT","NEFT","RTGS","ACU"],"answer":"EFT","chapter":44,"marks":1},{"question":"Under EFT , if customer gives an instruction to transfer the fund between 2pm to 4pm beneficiary gets credit on …………..","options":["Same day","Day one","Day two","Day three"],"answer":"Day two","chapter":44,"marks":1},{"question":"The service branch prepares the EFT data file by using software package supplied by …………….and transmits the same to the local RBI to be included for the settlement of 12 noon , 2 pm and 4 pm.","options":["Originating bank","Reserve Bank","IBA","Recipient bank"],"answer":"Reserve Bank","chapter":44,"marks":1},{"question":"Is it necessary to have the computer system  for branch for sending the remittance through EFT system? ………………..Yes or No","options":["Yes","No"],"answer":"No","chapter":44,"marks":1},{"question":"What is the benefit of EFT system?","options":["Auto reconciliation","Interbank TT service","Both above","Any one above"],"answer":"Both above","chapter":44,"marks":1},
  {"question":"NEFT is fastest option available for…………..transfers","options":["Inter city","Inter bank","Customer to customer","Bank to customer"],"answer":"Inter city","chapter":45,"marks":1},{"question":"The NEFT system uses the concept of centralised accounting system  and the bank account that is sending and receiving transfer instructions gets operated at one centre at…………..only.","options":["Delhi","Mumbai","Chennai","Kolkata"],"answer":"Mumbai","chapter":45,"marks":1},{"question":"Who can use NEFT?","options":["Individual","Firms","Corporate","Any one above"],"answer":"Any one above","chapter":45,"marks":1},{"question":"What is the acronym of Indian Financial System code?","options":["RTGS","NEFT","IFSC","EFT"],"answer":"IFSC","chapter":45,"marks":1},{"question":"IFSC is …..Digit alphanumeric code designing to identify bank branches in India.","options":["5","8","11","12"],"answer":"11","chapter":45,"marks":1},{"question":"Whether NEFT can be used to transfer the funds from NRO or NRE account?...Yes or No","options":["Yes","No"],"answer":"Yes","chapter":45,"marks":1},{"question":"Which country citizens in India can avail of NEFT as walk in customer?","options":["Nepal","Bhutan","Bangladesh","Sri Lanka"],"answer":"Nepal","chapter":45,"marks":1},
  {"question":"Under each category of SWIFT, various types of messages are sent / received by the bank and each of the messages are considered as ………………..","options":["Message Type","Numbered Message","Message group","Text message group"],"answer":"Message Type","chapter":46,"marks":1},{"question":"The sender , when he receives ……………from the SWIFT FIN centre , gets the legal protection for any dispute.","options":["Receipt","Acknowledge","ACK Copy","NAC copy"],"answer":"ACK Copy","chapter":46,"marks":1},{"question":"SWIFT assumes ………………..for the accuracy and timely delivery of all validated messages from the point they enter the network to the point they leave the network.","options":["Delivery","Acceptance","Financial liability","Correctness"],"answer":"Financial liability","chapter":46,"marks":1},{"question":"The Head quarter of SWIFT is Belgium ………………….","options":["USA","UK","Belgium","Hong Kong"],"answer":"Belgium","chapter":46,"marks":1},{"question":"On becoming the member the new member is allotted an address called……………of 8 characters.","options":["Bank identification code","Unique identification Number","Interbank Financial security code","Interbank Financial security code"],"answer":"Bank identification code","chapter":46,"marks":1},{"question":"Expand: BIC","options":["Business identification code","Business information code","Bank identification code","Bank information code"],"answer":"Bank identification code","chapter":46,"marks":1},{"question":"The serial number given against each category is known in SWIFT as………….","options":["Category code","Message code","SWIFT Code","Reference code"],"answer":"Category code","chapter":46,"marks":1},
  {"question":"The Indo –Nepal Remittance facility is ……………..remittance facility.","options":["One way","Two way","Both the above"],"answer":"One way","chapter":47,"marks":1},{"question":"A remitter can transfer funds up to INR ………..from any of the NEFT branches to beneficiary in Nepal.","options":["25,000","50,000","75,000","100,000"],"answer":"50,000","chapter":47,"marks":1},{"question":"Under the Indo remittance facility scheme the designated branch of …………..consolidates all remittances received during the day and remit to Nepal at the end of the day.","options":["Reserve Bank of India","State Bank of India","Originating Bank","Any bank"],"answer":"State Bank of India","chapter":47,"marks":1},{"question":"Nepal SBI Ltd has tied up with ………..in Nepal who would make arrangements for delivery of cash to the beneficiary","options":["Nepal Rashtra Bank","Money transfer company","All banks","Beneficiary bank"],"answer":"Money transfer company","chapter":47,"marks":1},{"question":"Charges for remittance arrangement up to Rs.5000 are Rs…………flat inclusive of service tax for every remittance.","options":["25","50","100","200"],"answer":"50","chapter":47,"marks":1},{"question":"Flat charges of Rs……………including the service tax is levied for remittance between Rs.5000 to Rs.50,000 under Indo Nepal remittance scheme.","options":["50","75","100","250"],"answer":"75","chapter":47,"marks":1},{"question":"Under Indo Nepal remittance scheme Remitter is allowed to remit maximum of ………..remittances in a year.","options":["10","12","15","20"],"answer":"12","chapter":47,"marks":1},
  {"question":"Banks keeps cash or balances with………………….","options":["Reserve Bank of India","Other commercial banks","Both above","Any one above"],"answer":"Both above","chapter":48,"marks":1},{"question":"Commercial Banks keeps cash with Reserve Bank of India for following purposes……….","options":["To meet statutory requirement","To make payment to other commercial banks","Both above","Any one above"],"answer":"Both above","chapter":48,"marks":1},{"question":"What banks are doing with excess money?","options":["Surrender Excess Money to RBI","Send to other banks currency chest","Send to other bank not having currency chest","All above"],"answer":"All above","chapter":48,"marks":1},{"question":"Coins for Rs. 150, Rs 500, and Rs.1000 have been issued as………..and have no commercial value.","options":["Celebration coins","Legal tender","Commemorative coins","Any one above"],"answer":"Commemorative coins","chapter":48,"marks":1},{"question":"small coins are taken by the banks on …………….","options":["Counting","Weight","all above"],"answer":"Weight","chapter":48,"marks":1},{"question":"The currency notes in the denomination of Rs. 100, Rs. 500, Rs. 100, Rs.50, Rs. 20, Rs.10 are called as …………………","options":["Exchange","Legal tender","Promissory notes","All above"],"answer":"Legal tender","chapter":48,"marks":1},{"question":"The notes of the denomination of Rs. 5, Rs 2, and Rs. 1 have been discontinued. What is the status of these notes which are in circulation?","options":["They are no more legal tender","They are legal tender","none of the above"],"answer":"They are legal tender","chapter":48,"marks":1},{"question":"In order to obviate the problem of storage of coins at the branches , aluminium coins of 5 paise, 10 paise, 20 paise , 25 paise, 50 paise and Rs. 1 directions given to bank is ………..","options":["Send to their own currency chest","Send to Reserve Bank","Send to Government of India Mint","All above"],"answer":"Send to Government of India Mint","chapter":48,"marks":1},{"question":"Detection and impounding of counterfeit notes can be impounded by …………….","options":["All the banks","Treasuries","Issue office of RBI","All above"],"answer":"All above","chapter":48,"marks":1},{"question":"A counterfeit notes detected in cash received by the bank / branch shall be impounded and informed to………………..","options":["Police authorities","Head office","RBI","All above"],"answer":"Police authorities","chapter":48,"marks":1},
  {"question":"Electronic banking includes……………..","options":["ATM  & Teller Machines","Internet banking","Both above","Any one above"],"answer":"Both above","chapter":49,"marks":1},{"question":"Each customer is provided with ATM card with unique………….","options":["Personal Identification Number","Access to ATM","Facilities to ATM","All above"],"answer":"Personal Identification Number","chapter":49,"marks":1},{"question":"Customer can withdraw Rs……………per withdraw from ATM not owned by the bank.","options":["3000","5000","10000","20000"],"answer":"10000","chapter":49,"marks":1},{"question":"What is the minimum amount that can be withdrawn from ATM?","options":["100","500","1000","2000"],"answer":"100","chapter":49,"marks":1},{"question":"Point of sales facility is available at any merchant establishment designated by Bank after process of …………….","options":["Due diligence","KYC","Limit","Genuineness"],"answer":"Due diligence","chapter":49,"marks":1},{"question":"Internet banking permits an account holder to access his account by ………….from home or other remote locations and issue instructions.","options":["Computer","ATM","Net banking","All above"],"answer":"Computer","chapter":49,"marks":1},
  {"question":"To ensure that an authorised person who is seeking the information , the customer would be required to state …………….., date of birth, address proof or any other unique information.","options":["ATM Pin","T-Pin","Internet pin","All above"],"answer":"T-Pin","chapter":50,"marks":1},{"question":"The information provided on telephone banking includes………………..","options":["Transfer of funds","Balance enquiry","Request for cheque book and statement","All above"],"answer":"All above","chapter":50,"marks":1},
  {"question":"Mobile banking is undertaking banking services using mobile phones that involves……….","options":["Debit","Credits","Both above","Only internet banking"],"answer":"Both above","chapter":51,"marks":1},{"question":"To ensure level playing field and considering that the technology is relatively new…………issued guidelines.","options":["Reserve Bank of India","Individual banks providing facilities","Indian Bank association","Any one above"],"answer":"Reserve Bank of India","chapter":51,"marks":1},{"question":"Only banks who have implemented ………..solutions would be permitted to provide mobile banking services.","options":["Core Banking","Internet banking","Electronic banking","Any one above"],"answer":"Core Banking","chapter":51,"marks":1},{"question":"Is it necessary for the customer to register to avail the mobile banking facility?.....Yes or No","options":["Yes","No"],"answer":"Yes","chapter":51,"marks":1},{"question":"Under mobile banking, transaction up to Rs………..can be facilitated by banks without end to end encryption.","options":["1000","3000","5000","10000"],"answer":"5000","chapter":51,"marks":1},{"question":"As a security principle, one of the factors for authentication shall be………….or any higher standard.","options":["ATM PIN","I-Pin","m-PIN","any one above"],"answer":"m-PIN","chapter":51,"marks":1},{"question":"In case of cash out , the maximum value of transfer through mobile banking shall be Rs………per transaction.","options":["10,000","20,000","20,000","50,000"],"answer":"10,000","chapter":51,"marks":1},
  {"question":"Which card issuer company’s charge cards are more in circulation?","options":["American Express","Diners Card","Both above","None of the above"],"answer":"Both above","chapter":52,"marks":1},{"question":"What is credit card?","options":["At the end of the month card holder should pay minimum amount","If not paid Interest will be levied at 2-3%","Both above","Where full amount is required to pay after receipt of statement"],"answer":"Both above","chapter":52,"marks":1},{"question":"Who are the major credit card issuer companies?","options":["Master card","Visa Card","Both above","American Express and Diners card"],"answer":"Both above","chapter":52,"marks":1},{"question":"If complaint does not get satisfactory response from the bank which is subsidiary of a bank within a maximum period of 30 days from the date of his lodging the complaint , he will have option to approach the …………………………..","options":["Reserve Bank","Head office of Bank","Banking Ombudsman","Court"],"answer":"Banking Ombudsman","chapter":52,"marks":1},{"question":"What is virtual card?","options":["Actual credit card with different name","Generated for internet transaction for one time transaction","Debit card","ATM card"],"answer":"Generated for internet transaction for one time transaction","chapter":52,"marks":1},{"question":"What is smart card?","options":["Normal credit card","Normal credit card with integrated circuit chip","Master Card","Visa Card"],"answer":"Normal credit card with integrated circuit chip","chapter":52,"marks":1},{"question":"An electronic purse is smart card that has transferred in to an amount of …………….","options":["Money","Credit card","Debit card","Master card"],"answer":"Money","chapter":52,"marks":1},{"question":"What is debit card?","options":["Similar to ATM card having unique number","Master Card","Visa card","Credit card"],"answer":"Similar to ATM card having unique number","chapter":52,"marks":1},{"question":"Banks may issue an online debit cards including ……………where there is an immediate debit to customers account and STP involved.","options":["Master debit Card","Visa Debit card","Cobranded debit card","Any one above"],"answer":"Cobranded debit card","chapter":52,"marks":1},{"question":"Whether banks are permitted to issue offline debit cards?","options":["Permitted","Not permitted","none of the above"],"answer":"Not permitted","chapter":52,"marks":1},
  {"question":"Who issued the guidelines for telemarketing?","options":["Respective banks","Department of Telecommunication","Head office of the Bank","Indian Bank Association"],"answer":"Department of Telecommunication","chapter":53,"marks":1},{"question":"Bank should ensure that all telemarketers engaged by them register themselves with …………….as telemarketers.","options":["DoT","Head office","RBI","IBA"],"answer":"DoT","chapter":53,"marks":1},{"question":"The registration issued by DoT to the telemarketer is valid for …………years","options":["3","5","7","10"],"answer":"10","chapter":53,"marks":1},{"question":"Telemarketers shall comply with …………….","options":["Guidelines for telemarketers","Directions issued by DoT","Orders by TRAI","All above"],"answer":"All above","chapter":53,"marks":1},{"question":"Telemarketer may surrender the registration by giving …………days notice to DoT.","options":["15","30","45","60"],"answer":"30","chapter":53,"marks":1},
  {"question":"……………….for doorstep banking should be prominently indicated on brochures offering door step banking.","options":["Charges","Services","Time schedule","Mode of communication"],"answer":"Charges","chapter":54,"marks":1},{"question":"What are the activities covered under doorstep banking?","options":["Pick up cash and instruments","Delivery of  cash","Delivery of demand drafts","All above"],"answer":"All above","chapter":54,"marks":1},{"question":"What are the modalities of delivery under doorstep banking?","options":["Own employees","Through agents","Any one above","Courier"],"answer":"Any one above","chapter":54,"marks":1},{"question":"How the risk is mitigated under door step banking?","options":["Agreement with customer","Bank policy","Board approved policy of the corporate","Written communication by client"],"answer":"Agreement with customer","chapter":54,"marks":1},
  {"question":"Safe deposit lockers facility is one that is offered by Banks in residential areas to help individuals to ……………………….","options":["Safeguard valuables","Deposit cash","Deposit eatable","All above"],"answer":"Safeguard valuables","chapter":55,"marks":1},{"question":"How the lockers are allotted by banks?","options":["On application","On the basis of deposit kept with bank","On the basis of wait list","Left to individual branch of the bank"],"answer":"On the basis of wait list","chapter":55,"marks":1},{"question":"What is the document required to execute by the individual while hiring the locker?","options":["Lease agreement","DPN","Locker agreement","All above"],"answer":"Lease agreement","chapter":55,"marks":1},{"question":"The relationship of Bank and hirer of the locker is………………..","options":["Banker –Customer","Lesser  - lessee","Donor – accepter","Lender - borrower"],"answer":"Lesser  - lessee","chapter":55,"marks":1},{"question":"Locker may be hired in a ………… name.","options":["Single","Jointly","Company","Any one above"],"answer":"Any one above","chapter":55,"marks":1},{"question":"Whether nomination facility is available with lockers?.........Yes or No","options":["Yes","No"],"answer":"Yes","chapter":55,"marks":1},{"question":"Access given to nominee / survivor gives the bank full discharge and bank should not insist on …………….","options":["Death certificate","Power of attorney","Succession certificate","Any other document"],"answer":"Succession certificate","chapter":55,"marks":1},
  {"question":"What is safe custody?","options":["Space given by bank for goods and valuable","Locker","Bank accepts valuable from customer for safe custody","Extra service only to HNI"],"answer":"Bank accepts valuable from customer for safe custody","chapter":56,"marks":1},{"question":"Whether bank can exercise general lien on items in safe custody?..........Yes or No","options":["Yes","No"],"answer":"No","chapter":56,"marks":1},{"question":"Items given for safe custody may be …………………….","options":["Open","Closed","Both","Either of a or b"],"answer":"Either of a or b","chapter":56,"marks":1},{"question":"When items are given in open status bank should…………….","options":["Take detailed note of items","List to be signed by customer","Witness should be obtained","All above"],"answer":"All above","chapter":56,"marks":1},{"question":"Banker will be held liable in case of safe custody if……………..","options":["Keep item open or easy to access","Vault is not strong  and kept with some other person","Stealing by bank employee","All above"],"answer":"All above","chapter":56,"marks":1},
];
